Guide to the Cleanth Brooks Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Others, 1943-86; Series V; 1; (2 boxes)
  - ROBERT PENN WARREN
    - Poetry
      - "Amazing Grace": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1842)
      - "Antinomies of Time": typescript, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1843)
      - "Audubon: A Vision and a Question for You": typescript, photocopy (Box 88, Folder 1844)
      - "Ballad: Between the Box Cars": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1845)
      - "Ballad of a Sweet Dream of Peace": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1846)
      - "Ballad of Billie Potts": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1847)
      - "Bicentennial Ode": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1848)
      - "By Way of Solution": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1849)
      - "The Day Dr. Know Did It": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1850)
      - "Debate: Question, Quarry, Dream": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1851)
      - "Dream of a Dream": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1852)
      - "Essay on the Human Understanding": typescript, photocopy (Box 88, Folder 1853)
      - "Fall Comes In Back-Country Vermont": printed version, 1965 Oct 23 (Box 88, Folder 1854)
      - "A Faring": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1855)
      - "Fox-fire": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1856)
      - "Garland For You: Poem": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 88, Folder 1857)
      - "Have you crouched with rifle in woods in autumn": typescript, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 1858)
      - "Homage to Dreiser": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1859)
      - "Homage to Emerson, On Night Flight to New York": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1860)
      - "Home Thoughts from Abroad, or": typescript, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1861)
      - "In the Turpitude of Time": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1862)
      - "Leaves of Our Maple": typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1863)
      - "Love at First Sight": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1864)
      - "Love's Parable": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1865)
      - "Lullaby: A Motion Like Sleep": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1866)
      - "The Mission": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1867)
      - "Nocturne: Traveling Saleman in Hotel Bed Room": typescript, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1868)
      - "Northford Swing": typescript, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1869)
      - "Notes On a Life To Be Lived": printed version, 1966 Feb 12 (Box 88, Folder 1870)
      - "Old Nigger on One-Mule Cart Encountered Late at Night When Driving Home from Party in the Back Country": typescript, photocopy (Box 88, Folder 1871)
      - "Original Sin: A Short Story": typescript, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1872)
      - "Part of a Short Story": typescript, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1873)
      - "Path": typescript, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1874)
      - "Penological Study: Southern Style": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1875)
      - "Penthelesea and Achilles: Fatal Interview": typescript carbon (Box 88, Folder 1876)
      - "Short Course in American History": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1877)
      - "Sila": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1878)
      - "Some Quiet, Plain Poems:" typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1879)
      - "Sunset Walk in Thaw-Time in Vermont": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1880)
      - "Todd County Dragon: To Jacob Boehme": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1881)
      - "Trying To Tell You Something": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1882)
      - "Two Pieces After Suetonius": typescript, 1958 Feb (Box 89, Folder 1883)
      - Unidentified, holograph, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1884)
    - Prefaces
      - Preface to unidentified book: typescript carbon, 1962 Mar 8 (Box 89, Folder 1885)
  - MISCELLANY
    - Adams, Percy G., "The Historical Importance of Assonance to Poetry": offprint, 1973 Jan (Box 89, Folder 1886)
    - Baker, John Ross, "Ideology and Literary Studies: A Dilemma": offprint, 1973 Mar (Box 89, Folder 1887)
    - Ballard, Charles, "Sand Creek" [poem]: typescript carbon (Box 89, Folder 1888)
    - Bentley, Eric, "A Note on the New Criticism": offprint, 1948 (Box 89, Folder 1889)
    - Bernard, Nova, various poems: typescript, photocopy, 1979 (Box 89, Folder 1890)
    - Betsky, [?], "Essay on F. R. Leavis": typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1891)
    - Buckley, F. Reid, "The Boys in Purple": pamphlet, 1982 (Box 89, Folder 1892)
    - Campbell, Harry M., "Arnold's Religion and the Theory of Fictions": offprint, 1967 (Box 89, Folder 1893)
    - "Criticism in America": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1894)
    - Drake, Robert, "Review of A Childhood: The Biography of a Place by Harry Crews": printed version, photocopy, 1980 (Box 89, Folder 1895)
    - Fleming, Robert E., "Hemingway's 'The Killers': The Map and the Territory": printed version, photocopy, 1984 (Box 89, Folder 1896)
    - Harris, Wendell V., "Adam Naming the Animals: Language, Context, and Meaning": offprint, 1986 (Box 89, Folder 1897)
    - Kerner, David, "Counterfeit Hemingway: A Small Scandal in Quotation Marks": offprint, 1985 Mar (Box 89, Folder 1898)
    - Kroll, Judith, various poems: typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1899)
    - Lentricchia, Frank, "Coleridge and Emerson: Prophets of Silence, Prophets of Language": offprint, 1973 Oct 22 (Box 89, Folder 1900)
    - McLuhan, Marshall
      - "Book Review of The Anatomy of Criticism by Northrup Frye": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1901)
      - "Book Review of James Joyce by Richard Ellmann": typescript carbon, ca. 1959 (Box 89, Folder 1902)
      - "Bacon Among the Historical Perspectivists": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1903)
      - "The Difficulties of Yvor Winters or Rymer Redivus": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1904)
      - "Media Log": typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1905)
      - "Media Log II": typescript, mimeograph, 1959 (Box 89, Folder 1906)
      - "Metaphor: The Analogy of Improper Proportions": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1907)
      - "MLA Seminar for English Literature and Communication Study": typescript, mimeograph (Box 89, Folder 1908)
    - Nims, John Frederick, "Review of The Winter Sea by Allen Tate": offprint, 1945 (Box 89, Folder 1909)
    - Silko, Leslie Marmon, "Love Poem": typescript, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1910)
    - "A Symposium: The Agrarians Today-- Five Questions": printed version, photocopy, annotated, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1911)
    - Vivas, Eliseo, "The Function of Criticism Today": typescript, mimeograph, 1949 Mar 14 (Box 89, Folder 1912)
    - Wellek, René, "Review of Against Criticism by Iain McGilchrist": typescript, photocopy, ca. 1982 (Box 89, Folder 1913)
- Personal Papers, 1927-86; Series VI; 1.5; (4 boxes)
  Series VI, Personal Papers (Boxes 90-93), is divided into four subseries, Biographical Material, Episcopal Church Material, Student Notebooks, and Miscellaneous Papers. Each subseries is alphabetically arranged.
  - BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
    - Appointment as Contributor to Encyclopaedia Britannica, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1914)
    - Appointment as Fellow of Davenport College, Yale University, 1948-63 (Box 90, Folder 1915)
    - Appointment as Guggenheim Fellow, 1960 Jun 27 (Box 90, Folder 1916)
    - Appointment as Honorary Consultant to Library of Congress, 1961 May 14 (Box 90, Folder 1917)
    - Appointment to Gray Professorship of Rhetoric at Yale University, 1960-61 (Box 90, Folder 1918)
    - Appointment to Read Chair of English at LSU, 1945-46 (Box 90, Folder 1919)
    - Biographical sketches, 1982-85 (Box 90, Folder 1920)
    - Brooks's teaching and writing career
      - LSU years, 1939-47 (Box 90, Folder 1921)
      - Departure from LSU for Yale, 1945-47 (Box 90, Folder 1922)
      - Arrival at Yale, 1947 (Box 90, Folder 1923)
      - Yale years, 1947-74, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1924-26)
      - Retirement years, 1975-78 (Box 90, Folder 1927)
    - Cleanthes, Classical references to, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1928)
    - Honorary degrees, awards, memberships, etc., 1963-76 (Box 90, Folder 1929)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1929-76, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1930)
      See also: Box 93, folders 1971-72
    - Photographs
      - Aiken, Conrad
        See: Box 90, folder 1938
      - Beatty, Richmond Croom
        See: Box 94, folder 1996
      - Bethurum, Dorothy
      - Brooks, Cleanth: single shots, 1976-85, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1931)
      - Brooks, Cleanth: group shots
        - American Embassy, London, 1966 Mar (Box 90, Folder 1932)
        - Fugitives and critics [extended group], 1956 May 4
          Related Materials
        - General, 1959-85, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1933)
        - Honorary degrees, Receiving of, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1934)
        - Japan, 1985 (Box 90, Folder 1935-36)
        - Jordan, 1984 (Box 90, Folder 1937)
        - Library of Congress, ca. 1950s (Box 90, Folder 1938)
        - Warren, Robert Penn et al., ca. 1980s (Box 90, Folder 1939)
      - Brooks, Edith Amy Blanchard ("Tinkum") (Mrs. Cleanth Brooks)
        See: Box 90, folders 1932, 1933, 1935-36
      - Brooks, James William ("Jimbo"), 1967 Apr (Box 90, Folder 1940)
      - Cheney, Brainard
      - Cobb, William C.
      - Cowan, Louise
      - Davidson, Donald
      - Elliott, William Yandell
      - Hirsch, Sidney M.
      - Jacobs, Robert D.
      - Kroll, Judith and Rafil (son), 1981-83 (Box 90, Folder 1941)
      - Lewis, Cecil Day, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1942)
      - Lytle, Andrew
      - Meredith, Burgess
      - Moore, Merrill
      - Owsley, Frank
      - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1939-72, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1943)
      - Purdy, Rob Roy
      - Raine, Kathleen, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1944)
      - Ransom, John Crowe
      - Rubin, Lewis
      - Spender, Stephen (Box 90, Folder 1945)
      - Starr, Alfred
      - Stevenson, Alec Brock
      - Stewart, Randall
      - Tassin, Anthony, 1966 Feb (Box 90, Folder 1946)
      - Tate, Allen
      - Thorp, Willard
      - Toledano, Cleanth Brooks (namesake), ca. 1970s (Box 90, Folder 1947)
      - Warren, Gabriel and Rosanna Phelps, 1964-82, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1948)
      - Warren, Robert Penn, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1949)
        See also: Box 90, folder 1939 and Box 94, folder 1996
      - Watkins, Vernon, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1950)
      - Wills, Jesse Ely
      - Wimsatt, James and Nancy, 1984 Dec 28 (Box 91, Folder 1951)
      - Wimsatt, William K. ("Bill"), 1954-69 (Box 91, Folder 1952)
      - Unidentified, 1967-68, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1953)
    - Salary matters, 1944-60 (Box 91, Folder 1954)
  - EPISCOPAL CHURCH MATERIAL
    - Anglican Church of North America, Establishment of, 1977-78 (Box 91, Folder 1955)
    - Anglican Guild of Scholars, 1984 Jan (Box 91, Folder 1956)
    - Episcopal Church, General, 1986, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1957)
    - Ordination of women as priests, 1975-78, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1958)
    - Parker, Dorothy Mills, "The Prayer Book Issue, A Survey": typescript, photocopy, 1978 Jan 8 (Box 91, Folder 1959)
    - Prayer Book revision: discussion by Anglican Guild of Scholars members Barr, Pottle, Brooks, and Marshall (Box 91, Folder 1960)
    - Prayer Book revision, General, 1973-86 (Box 91, Folder 1961)
      See also: Box 78, folders 1578-81
    - Society for the Preservation of the Book of Common Prayer, 1981, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1962)
    - Warden of St. Andrew's Church, Northfield, Conn., Retirement as, 1964 (Box 91, Folder 1963)
  - STUDENT NOTEBOOKS
    - Anglo-Saxon prose, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1964)
    - Chaucer, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1965)
    - Chaucer, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1966-67)
    - Essays on Chaucer, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1968)
    - Revision, 1300-1580, 1927-30 (Box 91, Folder 1969)
    - Fifteenth Century, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1970)
    - Bibliography, 1932 (Box 92, Folder 1971)
    - Shakespeare, 1927-30 (Box 92, Folder 1972)
    - Shakespeare, 1929 (Box 92, Folder 1973)
    - Spencer and Milton, 1928-30 (Box 92, Folder 1974)
    - Milton and seventeenth century, 1927-30 (Box 92, Folder 1975)
    - Seventeenth-century poetry, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1976)
    - Seventeenth century, Dryden, Restoration drama, Donne, and metaphysicals, 1927-30 (Box 92, Folder 1977)
    - Dryden, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1978)
    - Seventeenth century and Dryden, 1927-30 (Box 93, Folder 1979)
    - Restoration drama (Box 93, Folder 1980)
  - MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
    - Foreign friends (Box 93, Folder 1981)
    - Printed material, 1972-86 (Box 93, Folder 1982)
    - Receipts, 1983-86 (Box 93, Folder 1983)
    - War ration book, 1943 (Box 93, Folder 1984)
    - General, 1983-86, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1985)
- Additions Since 1978, 1926-1994; Series VII; 29.92; (34 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized chronologically by accession.
  Series VII. Additions Since 1978, contains research material, correspondence, writings by Brooks and others, and personal papers. Named folders consist chiefly of writings.
  Former call numbers: Uncat Za Ms 595, Uncat Za Ms 420, Uncat Za Ms 422, Uncat Za Ms 445, and Uncat Za Ms 459.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Cleanth Brooks, 1978-1995, and John Walsh, 1995.
  - June 1978 Acquisition, 0.08' (1 box)
    Gift of Cleanth Brooks.
    Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 595.
    - Photostats of the Percy-Shenstone letters in the British Library, undated (Box 96 (Oversize))
  - December 1994 Acquisition, 23.25' (25 boxes)
    Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 420.
    - Photograph and Faulkner letter, 1940, undated (Box 97)
    - Writings on New Criticism and Nathaniel Hawthorne, undated (Box 97)
    - Garrigues, aura, 1979 December 10 (Box 97)
    - "Gresset and Samway, eds.", 1983 (Box 97)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1989-1994, undated (Box 97)
    - Galloway, Wallace D., 1990 March (Box 97)
    - Writings of others, 1983-1993, undated (Box 97)
    - Hoffman, Jamie, 1987-1991; 3 folders (Box 97)
    - Hoffman, Daniel, undated (Box 97)
    - Hunter, George K., 1983-1990 (Box 97)
    - Johnson, Thomas Hawkins, 1992, undated; 5 folders (Box 97)
    - "J" - "L" general, 1972-1991, undated (Box 97)
    - Leff, Jonathan, 1988, undated (Box 97)
    - The Yale Review, 1981 (Box 97)
    - "From Eden to Babylon" by Andrew Nelson Lytle, page proofs (photocopy), 1989 (Box 97)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and articles, 1990-1993, undated (Box 98)
    - "Important Notes on dialects", undated (Box 98)
    - Fischer, David Hackett, 1988, undated (Box 98)
    - "Yale alumni session...", 1987, undated (Box 98)
    - "Alumni Talk - Southern dialect, Southern Dialect Notes", 1987 (Box 98)
    - "The Language of the American South", 1988 (Box 98)
    - "Miscellaneous Southern Dialect Forms", 1983-1985, undated (Box 98)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1926-1985, undated (Box 98)
    - "Language and Dialect," notebook, undated (Box 98)
    - "Early American English Pronunciation as Reflected by the Spelling of a Naive Scribe from the Massachusetts Bay Colony in the Late 17th Century", 1983 (Box 98)
    - "The Loss of R", undated (Box 98)
    - Unidentified notes, undated (Box 98)
    - "Notes on June Lecture, 24 May Version", 1983, undated (Box 98)
    - "Old-time Talk We Still de Talkem Here!", 1987 (Box 98)
    - "Gentry of Kent & Other History", undated (Box 98)
    - "The Language of the American South", undated (Box 98)
    - "Cruise Lectures", undated (Box 98)
    - "Letters To and From McDavid + Newfoundland Article", 1958-1984, undated (Box 98)
    - "De Song of Solomon" and notes, 1989, undated (Box 98)
    - "Language of the American South," reviews, 1986-1987 (Box 98)
    - "Wyld on London Eng Newfoundland", 1988, undated (Box 98)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1987-1989 (Box 98)
    - Notes for Southern speech, undated (Box 98)
    - "Synthesis and Generalizations", 1984, undated; 2 folders (Box 98)
    - Card catalogue, undated (Box 98)
    - "List of Books and Articles on Southern Dialect", undated (Box 98)
    - Notes on Southern dialect, undated (Box 98)
    - "The 'Southern' Pronunciation: Its Origins", undated (Box 98)
    - "Language of the South June 5, 1987, Miscellaneous Notes", 1986, undated (Box 98)
    - "Black English", 1972-1987, undated (Box 98)
    - "New England", 1927-1985, undated (Box 98)
    - "Black English Controversy", 1974-1984, undated (Box 98)
    - "Appalachian Dialect", 1986-1987 (Box 98)
    - Southern Dialect notes, 1987, undated (Box 98)
    - Printed material on Southern dialect, 1960-1986, undated (Box 98)
    - "Southern Dialect Bibliography", 1982, undated (Box 98)
    - "Quotations From Southernors - Extras and Spares", undated (Box 98)
    - "Tangier Island" (empty folder), undated (Box 98)
    - "Tristan Da Cunha", undated (Box 98)
    - "Xerox Material for Alumni, June 2-4", undated (Box 98)
    - "FMR," English edition Vol. V, 1986 (Box 99)
    - "A" general, 1978-1992, undated (Box 99)
    - Atterbury-Jenney, Judy, 1991 July 16 (Box 99)
    - "B" general, 1971-1992, undated; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - Beck, Charlotte, undated; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - Blanchard, Catherine, 1977, 1986 (Box 99)
    - Bollenbach, Carolyn, 1985 (Box 99)
    - Brodsky, Louis Daniel, 1986-1989; 5 folders (Box 99)
    - "B" - "C" general, 1986-1989, undated (Box 99)
    - Cherry, Kelly, 1989-1992, undated (Box 99)
    - Clark; Core, 1984-1992 (Box 99)
    - "Cricket" children's magazine, 1983-1985 (Box 99)
    - Crowder, Ashby Bland, 1989, undated (Box 99)
    - Cuddy, Lois, 1978-1989, undated (Box 99)
    - "Cumberland Review - Poems 1992" (Box 99)
    - Dorsey, Laurens Macdonald, 1984, undated (Box 99)
    - "D" - "F" general, 1983-1992, undated (Box 99)
    - "Proposal for the Preservation and Conservation of The Flannery O'Connor Manuscripts", 1989 November; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - "F" general, 1984-1993 (Box 100)
    - Francisco, Edward, 1985 (Box 100)
    - "M" general, 1982-1992 (Box 100)
    - Magnuson, James, 1989; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - Moise, Edwin, undated (Box 100)
    - Moise; Millichap, undated (Box 100)
    - Momberger, Philip, undated (Box 100)
    - Momberger; Montesi, 1984, undated (Box 100)
    - Montgomery, Marion, 1982-1985 (Box 100)
    - Montgomery, Michael, 1988 May (Box 100)
    - "M" - "N" general, 1988-1993, undated (Box 100)
    - "North Ireland - Cruise O'Brien", 1979-1982 (Box 100)
    - "O" general, 1980-1993 (Box 100)
    - "P" general, 1983-1992 (Box 100)
    - Pope, Liston, undated (Box 100)
    - Prunty, Wyatt, 1982-1988, undated; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - "R" general, 1979-1993, undated; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - Rio-Jelliffe, R., 1983 (Box 101)
    - "S" general, 1984-1986, undated (Box 101)
    - "Shaheen Material", 1983-1984, undated (Box 101)
    - Sensibar, Judith, 1987-1989, undated (Box 101)
    - Sepich, John, 1991-1992 (Box 101)
    - Sheppard, Patricia, 1984 (Box 101)
    - Shusterman, Richard, 1988, undated (Box 101)
    - Simpson, Lewis, 1987-1994, undated; 3 folders (Box 101)
    - Spencer, Elizabeth, 1989, 1992 (Box 101)
    - "Spurlin Collection on New Criticism", 1993 (Box 101)
    - "S" general, 1987-1993, undated (Box 101)
    - "Sykes's F 'n Religion", 1986 (Box 101)
    - "T" - "W" general, 1985-1992, undated (Box 101)
    - "W" - "Y" general, 1971-1993, undated (Box 101)
    - The Sewanee Review, printed issues, 1980-1983; 3 folders (Box 102)
    - PMLA, Vol. 98 No. 3, 1983 May (Box 102)
    - "Hillis Miller, Gerald Graf, et. al.", 1976-1981, undated (Box 102)
    - Wellek, René, 1980-1986; 2 folders (Box 102)
    - "Criticism & the 'New Criticism'", 1968-1976, undated (Box 102)
    - "Deconstruction and 'Oresteia'", 1985 March 15 (Box 102)
    - "The Interests of Criticism", 1969; 2 folders (Box 102)
    - Tassin, Anthony G., 1992; 2 folders (Box 102)
    - Gaugliardo, Huey S. dissertation on Brooks, 1979 August; 2 folders (Box 102)
    - "Duke U. and New Historicism - De Man", 1983-1988 (Box 102)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1979-1984, undated (Box 102)
    - "The 'New Criticism' Tearsheets and Xerox Copies", 1949-1980, undated (Box 102)
    - "Essays Bearing on the 'New Criticism'", 1959-1979 (Box 103)
    - "Southern Review Celebration 1985" (Box 103)
    - "Notes and Articles on the Church, Miscellaneous", 1988-1989, undated (Box 103)
    - Clippings, 1984-1988 (Box 103)
    - Copies of articles, 1970-1986 (Box 103)
    - Gardner, John, 1980-1981, undated (Box 103)
    - Hodges, William, "The Phantom Heart," typescript, 1978 (Box 103)
    - "The State of the Seminaries", 1970-1982, undated (Box 103)
    - "Notes on Literature and Religion (and Related Matters)", 1980, undated (Box 103)
    - Church related material, 1981-1982, undated; 2 folders (Box 103)
    - "Responses to 'God, Gallup, and the Episcopalians'", 1980-1982, undated; 2 folders (Box 103)
    - "Anglican-Catholic Affairs", 1972-1981, undated; 2 folders (Box 103)
    - Episcopal Book of Common Prayer material, 1977-1982, undated (Box 103)
    - "Extreme (?) Protestanism", 1981 (Box 103)
    - "Elinor Jacobs and Pecusa", 1980, undated (Box 103)
    - "Theological Reading List", 1950-1975,undated (Box 103)
    - "Religion: Enrico Cantore", 1971-1974, undated (Box 103)
    - "P. B. Controversy New England" (empty folder), undated (Box 103)
    - "New England Anglican", 1981 (Box 103)
    - Anglican material, 1973-1981 (Box 103)
    - "Homosexuality", 1978 (Box 103)
    - "Material for PB Essays (Less Recent)", 1963-1980 (Box 103)
    - "St. Louis Affirmation", 1977 (Box 103)
    - "Essays on Pecusa and the PB", 1969-1979 (Box 103)
    - "Ordination Controversy", 1977-1980 (Box 103)
    - Findlay, Jean, 1981 (Box 103)
    - "Post St. Louis, 1977 and After", 1962-1981 (Box 103)
    - "The Silliness of Pecusa", 1980 (Box 103)
    - The Southern Review, notes, undated (Box 103)
    - Sensibar, Judith, 1986-1987, undated (Box 104)
    - "Personal Letters", 1992, undated (Box 104)
    - "Yale Charity Beneficiary Gift", 1992 (Box 104)
    - "Darou Papera", 1993 (Box 104)
    - "L.S.U. Civil War Center", 1993 (Box 104)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1978-1994, undated; 8 folders (Box 104)
    - "Honorary Degrees", 1985 (Box 104)
    - "Southern 'Academy'", 1984-1987, undated (Box 104)
    - "University Offers", 1974-1977 (Box 104)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 104)
    - "Letters To Be Answered, Jan, 1993", 1992 (Box 104)
    - "Societies...", 1992-1993 (Box 104)
    - "Letters To Be Answered, August (Late)", 1989-1993, undated (Box 104)
    - "Paradise Lost", 1993 (Box 104)
    - "Clusters", 1959-1989, undated (Box 104)
    - Percy, Walker, 1986-1988 (Box 104)
    - Ferris, Bill, 1986 (Box 104)
    - Faulkner and Yoknapatawpha Conference material, 1987 (Box 104)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1985-1992, undated (Box 104)
    - "C. T. Indra Material", 1990-1993, undated (Box 104)
    - "Wimsatt Bios", 1975 (Box 104)
    - "PBS 'Theological Journal'", 1982-1985 (Box 104)
    - "Misc. Letters - Refile", 1991-1992, undated (Box 104)
    - "Misc. Letters and Notes 1988", 1987-1988, undated (Box 104)
    - The New Criterion, vol. 10 no. 2, 1991 October (Box 105)
    - Professional correspondence, 1988-1991, undated; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1992-1994, undated (Box 105)
    - "Letters To Be Answered Soon", 1993-1994, undated (Box 105)
    - "1988 Engagements", 1988-1989 (Box 105)
    - "Letters Answered July 1989", 1988-1990 (Box 105)
    - Darou, Ait, 1993, undated (Box 105)
    - "S.U. Review Offices", 1993, undated (Box 105)
    - Writings of others, 1991-1993, undated; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1957-1994, undated; 3 folders (Box 105)
    - "Letters From Special Friends...", 1990-1993, undated (Box 105)
    - Scully, John David, 1989 (Box 105)